According to YouTube statistics, only a
small percentage of people that watch my
videos are actually subscribed. So if
you end up liking this video, consider
subscribing. It's free and you can
always un They had this thing called
>> the sideshow museum. And it was a
[music] museum of circus freak shows
from the 1800s. Like stuff that had been
in these circus sideshows. [music] They
had the shadow box hanging on the wall.
And there's a dried out turd. And it
says it's Abraham Lincoln's final turd.
Come on. [music] So it says on the card,
it said when he arrived at Ford's
Theater, he had to drop a deuce. And so
before he got seated, he went [music] to
the men's room. And he dropped a deuce
in the chamber pot.
>> And then he went back to [music] watch
the play.
>> And he got shot. Somebody had the
presence of mind to [__] up. And they
say presence of mind over the sickness.
[music] Well, there are a lot of Lincoln
collectors out there. It's very
competitive. I see an article in the
[music] Washington Post about 6 months
later saying it's going out of business
and they're going to auction everything
off. So I told my wife, I'm buying that
turd.
She's [music] like, Oh, no, you're not.
I said, Oh, yes, I am. I'm buying that
[music] turd. My wife and I actually had
a strong disagreement about this. I go
to the auction and I I top out at 1,200
bucks. It ended up going for five
[music] grand. So the guy that ended up
buying it sends it to some company for a
DNA sample. And what they found was it
had [music] like microscopic bits of a
Necco Wafer in it. But Necco Wafers
weren't invented until 1880. It wasn't
his.
It wasn't [music] his. It was some
random guy's turd
>> that somebody paid $5,000
for. It was worth it. Mhm. It was worth
it. And another thing, too. And maybe
this is getting a little too personal.
But you really get to see who your
friends are. Oh, yeah, I'm sure. And
they're not the people you think they
are. Mhm.
>> So it's it's interesting because, you
know, you and I didn't overlap at the
agency.
>> No, I left in uh thanks. I left in 2004.
Four, yeah. And I came in 2007.
>> my resignation was effective in 2005.
Right. But
the one charge that that stuck for you
for the disclosure of a of a secret
identity.
>> Right. Um
>> The um Intelligence Identities
Protection Act.
>> Right. Was Deuce Martinez. No. It wasn't
Deuce.
>> No, no. Oh, it was somebody else. The
name was never made public. Ah.
>> See, this is the thing about Deuce
Martinez. They charged me with
espionage, saying that I outed Deuce
Martinez. Deuce Martinez is on [__]
LinkedIn, Central Intelligence Agency
Targeting Officer. Right. It's like,
well, you charged me with espionage, the
guy's on [__] LinkedIn. So, he pulls
out the the Polaroids. And again, these
are like hardcore
gay, you know, [music] anal.
And he lays them out.
And uh
he says, "Is this [music] torture? Are
the These men, they're torturing each
other. Should they be sent to
Guantanamo?" And these guys are old, so
they're like they have their their
trifocals on, and they're like One of
them picks it up and he goes like this.
He goes,
Oh.
Not good. [music]
This haram.
Not good. And the other one, he hands it
to the other one. Ah, no, no, no.
This not good.
And they just set it down.
And they just look at him.
But dammit, [music]
nothing's happening.
>> Another experience that I had that
troubled me deeply. I was serving in
Pakistan at the [music] time, and I was
staying in a small guest house because
it was safer than a big hotel. Sure
enough, the big hotel was [music] blown
up, and 45 people were killed while I
was living there. But I left my guest
house at a different time, like I did
every day, and took a different route,
like I did every day, to go to work. And
I noticed that a man on a motorcycle
wearing a red helmet was trying very
hard to stay in my [music] blind spot. I
worked 12, 14 hours, whatever it was
that day, and I left, and it was dark,
and sure enough, there he [music] was
again. There's a definition of
surveillance, it's multiple sightings at
time and distance. So, I've seen him
multiple times at different times of the
day, and at different [music] places.
I'm definitely under surveillance. I got
up at 5:00 in the morning, got in the
car, drove a block,
>> [music]
>> there he was again.
So, when I got to the to the office, I
said to the security officer, "I am
under surveillance.
>> [music]
>> I'm 100% sure that I'm under
surveillance." He said, "Well, let's
wait until the the chief comes in." When
the chief finally came in, I told him
the story, and he said, "Well,
>> [music]
>> you know what you have to do." I said,
"I know.
I'm going to kill him if I see him this
afternoon."
I was worried about it all day, and
[music] all my coworkers came up to me
that day to slap me on the back and say,
"Don't worry. We're all going to be out
there. We're going to have a whole
security team." I said, "I know, but I
never killed anybody before, and I'm so
worried that he's going to kill me
before I get a clear shot at him."
That afternoon, [music]
I had a meeting at a safe house that we
shared with the local service.
>> [music]
>> And
on my way out at the end of the meeting,
and I don't know why I did this, but I
turned around and I said, "General, are
you following me?"
And he said, [music] "No, why?" And I
said, "Because I'm under surveillance,
and if I see this guy again, I'm going
to kill him."
And I never saw him again.
I learned later
that several of their officers were
sitting around [music] and saying, "You
know, that new American guy, he's such a
nice guy. Nobody's that nice. I wonder
if he's being nice just to try to make
us drop our guard." And they decided to
put the worst surveillance officer in
their entire intelligence service
[music]
on me.
And if I hadn't said something that
afternoon, he would be in the ground
[music] today. Like the most famous guy
on the internet. Now, I don't recognize
your normal voice. It's killing me. I
know, right?
I don't know how this happened.
It just happened like literally
overnight. It just happened.
Can we pull up the latest one that we
put [music] up, Dave? Yeah. Let's get
John's live reaction. So, when this was
happening, when you and I did episodes
278 [music] and 279 together, which was
a year ago,
I remember this is probably [music] like
an hour 20 something minutes into the
first episode, and I remember this whole
Lincoln thing [music] coming up out of
nowhere. I'm like, "God, this is cool.
He's a Lincoln collector." And then you
look at me with a dead straight face
[music] and you're like, "Yeah, I was
trying to buy Lincoln's last turd." And
I at [music] the time we had Alessio in
the studio and I'm I'm I'm like turning
to Alessio like this this [__]
shits.
And then you're like, "Oh, yeah, I was
trying to buy it." So, when this all
started to break like Danny
on on our editing team and and I were
we're looking [music] at stuff. I'm
like, "You got to make the Lincoln
shits."
So, he he did. Let's run it.
>> [music]
>> And it was a museum of circus freak
shows from the 1800s. Like stuff that
had been in these circus side shows.
They had a shadow box hanging on the
wall. And there's dried out turd.
And it says it's Abraham [music]
Lincoln's final turd. Come on. So, it
says on the card, it said when he
arrived at [music] Ford's Theater, he
had to drop a deuce. And so, before he
got seated, he went to the men's room.
And he dropped [music]
a deuce in the chamber pot. And then he
went back to watch the play. And he got
shot.
Somebody had the presence of mind. to
[music] [__] out.
And they say presence of mind under the
sickness. Wow. There are a lot of
Lincoln collectors out there. [laughter]
I see an article in the newspaper about
six months later saying it's going out
of business and they're going to auction
[music] everything off. So, I told my
wife, I'm buying that turd.
She's like, No, you're not. I said, Oh,
yes, I am. I'm buying that turd. My wife
and I actually had a strong [music]
disagreement about this. We go to the
auction and I I topped out at 1,200
And then it goes for five grand. So, the
guy that ended up buying it sends it to
[music] some company for a DNA sample.
And what they found was it had like
microscopic bits of Neko Wafer in it,
but Neko Wafers weren't invented until
1880.
It wasn't a [__]
It wasn't his.
It was two two random guy's turd. And
that's something people paid $5,000
for.
>> [laughter]
>> That is one of my better stories. Oh my
god.
Are you familiar with black Twitter at
all? No. Oh, you're not. You need to
familiarize yourself. They love you.
[music] You really?
>> like, "Yo, this [__] John crazy,
yo.
This some words I'm not allowed to say.
This [__] out here just saying
straight cap but it's real.
And I'm I'm [__] dying and breathing
this stuff. And [music] I'm telling you
it happened literally overnight
and I don't understand [music] why. I
know you don't. I mean you're like for
people that don't know you personally,
which is pretty much everyone out there
listening like you've lived this amazing
life and done all [music] all these
incredible things or whatever, but it's
always
>> assigned to Iraq
and um
I immediately became Saddam Hussein's
classified biographer in the
intelligence community. So while the
Soviet Union is falling apart and those
analysts are becoming big stars, I
focused on Iraq and then much to my
shock and the world's shock, 9 months
later Iraq invaded Kuwait and overthrew
the Kuwaiti royal family and seized
Kuwait's oil fields.
Uh this was a a naked act of aggression
and war.
And so um I walked in that morning. I
got up early because we knew that the
invasion was coming. We predicted 30
days before that Saddam would invade
Kuwait. But um
I got into the office early and my boss
uh sort of intercepted me and said don't
take your jacket off, we're going to the
White House. And I'd never been to the
White House before. So we we got in a
car, we drove to the White House and we
were escorted into the Oval Office. And
keep in mind, I was 25 years old at the
time.
And you walk into the Oval Office and
here's the president, the vice
president, the national security
advisor, the CIA director, my boss and
me.
And the the mood is very heavy.
So everybody sits down and the president
says, "Well,
now what do we do?"
And then everybody turns and looks at
me.
And it took me a second to get my
bearings.
And I said, "Well,
the Kuwaiti government's been
overthrown. The Iraqi government
announced this morning that they had
installed Ahmad al-Khatib as the
occupation governor of of Kuwait. I
said, "Unfortunately,
we happen to know a lot about Ahmad
al-Khatib. He got a medical degree at
the American University of Beirut, and
his
college roommate was George Habash, and
together
they created the Popular Front for the
Liberation of Palestine."
And the vice president says, "Jesus
Christ."
And I thought, "Wow, this is this is
bad."
We finished the briefing, got up and
walked out, and two things happened. My
boss said to me,
"There's something you need to
understand."
He said, "I'm not sure that you're
appreciating the importance of what's
happening.
It's not unusual for a country that we
cover to go to war.
It's highly unusual for a country that
we cover to go to war with us.
And so,
we sent the largest army deployed since
the end of the Vietnam War.
We invaded Kuwait. We liberated it.
And then, uh,
the rest is history.
>> [music]
[music]